Amirhossein SEFATI

Sasanipour Street, Tehran, Iran | +98 935 4237 134 ahsefati77@gmail.com | www.ahsefati.ir



Professional summary

Motivated "Computer Science" with 3 years of progressive experience in the Internet of Things (IoT) and protocols of networks layers. Offering expertise in programming with aptitude in learning new fields. Energetic self-starter and team builder able to navigate high-stress situations and achieve goals on time. Interested in field of Algorithms to improve Internet and Network design.

Work history

July 2019 - current

Industrial Server Designer for IoT devices

Tinaio co.

Tehran

- I design server and back-end programs. I want to know more about how to design algorithms for communications between devices to decrease costs and speedup responses.
- Simulating some parts of IoT devices for smart connecting with each other. I used to work
 with MQTT-SN protocol and it's algorithm to have smart devices connected to main server
 with lowest headers.
- Familiar with "Wireshark" network analyzer.

October 2018 - current

Web Developer and Designer

Tipica co.

Tehran

- Designing, implementing and monitoring web pages and sites for continuous improvement in a fast-paced environment.
- Managing the team at meetings with executives, and discussing about project goals.
- Employing programming capabilities in PHP, MySQL and JavaScript and other libraries as needed.
- Familiar with TCP/IP protocols and congestion control mechanisms.
- Familiar with Machine Learning concepts and basics with knowledge of python programming.

Skills

Electrical Skills:

- MATLAB programming
- Simulink simulations
- Proteus simulations
- Python programming
- Arduino programming (C++)
- ARM programming (C)
- Altium Designer

Computer Skills:

- Java programming
- JavaScript programming
- Php programming
- MySQL database
- HTML5 and CSS3
- Wireshark analyzer
- Data structure and Algorithm Design
- MQTT protocol

Education

2016-current

Bachelor of Electrical Engineering

Amirkabir University of Technology

- Having an "A" GPA
- Working in Innovation and Technology Center (ITC) in Electrical engineering department
- Holding and teaching "IoT platform design" course in ITC
- Participating in several conferences about Industrial problems and how to solve them with low-budget

2018-current

Bachelor of Computer Engineering

Amirkabir University of Technology

- Field of "Software engineering"
- Having an "A" GPA
- Participating in several labs about Software design, Operating systems,
 Computer network, Multi-Thread programming and etc
- Creating a web-app site for projects about developing online services in some courses
- Interested in creating simulator and plotter apps like MATLAB-Simulink

2020 - current

Bachelor of Computer Engineering

Amirkabir University of Technology

- Field of "Artificial Intelligence"
- Having an "A" GPA
- Interested to create simulations of human and behavior of him/her.

Tips:

- I study Electrical and Computer engineering in Amirkabir university simultaneously having two separate student IDs for each of them. In our education system, students of "Computer Engineering" must study in two fields! So I study "Software Engineer" and "Artificial Intelligence".
- I am so interested in learning new things and in my opinion, I always learn fast!
- I have this ability to work and study all day long.